TEDLA ALEMU

Full Stack Developer Washington, DC

Mobile: (202) 460-2912 tedlayea@gmail.com https://tedlayea.github.io/

Experienced, skilled and confident **full-stack developer** who is passionate about using new technologies to bring out the best possible solution. I am a fast learner, and I value goal oriented and multicultural teams.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-end: JavaScript | jQuery | HTML5 | CSS3 | Bootstrap | AngularJS | ReactJS | Redux

Back-end/ Full stack: Ruby | Sinatra | Rails | Node.js | Express.js

Database: Ms-SQL Server | PostgreSQL | ActiveRecord | MongoDB | Mongoose

Other Tools: Wordpress | Postman | MS Office | Git | Github | Cloud9 | Selenium | JIRA

Platforms: Windows | Linux | Mac OS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

Peglu, Washington, DC September 2017 - Present

- · Reviewed major system enhancements and architecture of the existing application.
- Researched and designed new support technologies and developed customer based features using Ruby on Rails.
- Executed the enhancements of an existing application, supported product migration and deployment of the app.

Full Stack Developer Immersive Student

General Assembly, Washington, DC

May 2017 - August 2017

Project 1: Tedpark: an app that helps you remember where you parked with just one click.

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, ActiveRecord, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, and Heroku.

Project 2: Brew Mood: an app that prevents you from driving under the influence by checking your blood alcohol content.

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Ruby on Rails, AngularJS and PostgreSQL.

Project 3: e-Business Card: an app that stores and organizes business cards electronically.

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, AngularJS, and MongoLab.

Web Developer

Jimma University, Jimma, Ethiopia

April 2015 - February 2016

Project : Website Development

- Designed a website to facilitate learning-teaching system.
- Created website using HTML, CSS, and draw.io in order to fulfill the requirements listed in the design phase.
- Tested the website functionality before production and during the production phase using Selenium WebDriver.

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Selenium WebDriver.

Instructor and Researcher

Jimma University, Jimma, Ethiopia

November 2011 - September 2012

- Delivered, advised, coordinated and managed courses, programs, and events for engineering students.
- Led a team of six in modularizing and reviewing curriculum to improve the current education system.

EDUCATION

General Assembly, Washington, DC, Full Stack Web Development

July 2017

University of Trento, Italy M.Sc. in Engineering

March 2015

Full stack developer (Volunteer Activity)

Code for DC, Washington, DC

July 2017 - August 2017

Project 1: DC Abortion Fund: Ruby on Rails app for those who cannot afford the full cost of abortion care.

Project 2: District Housing: Ruby on Rails app that helps caseworkers to simplify filling multiple PDF applications.